ALEXEY DAVLETSHIN

C, C++, Python and Swift developer

Dolpogrudny, Russia @ naylrush@gmail.com in naylrush

naylrush

J +7 (963) 633-61-05

EDUCATION

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology (MIPT)

Bachelor of Applied Mathematics and Informatics at Phystech School of Applied Mathematics and Informatics

2018-2022

Dolgoprudny, Russia

Studied courses:

- Algorithms and Data Structures, Programming in C++
- Product Analysis by Yandex.Taxi
- Probability Theory, Mathematical Statistics
- Concurrency
- Computer Architecture and OS
- Calculus, Linear Geometry and others

Coursera:

Profile

- Swift 5 iOS Application Developer [Link]
- iOS-developing: Swift, UI and Concurrency RUS [Link]

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Engineer

Huawei HiSilicon Kirin CPU Russia

August 2020 - March 2021

- Moscow, Russia
- Optimized CMake build of the project and the project component, which reduced the running time and reduced memory usage.
- Rewritten several tools in the Rust.

iOS Engineer

COS&ht

July 2018 - August 2018

- Dolgoprudny, Russia
- I was learning Swift and developing a b2b app that displays emergency events on the map.
- Implemented the OpenStreetMap map and the list of events which are the basis of the app.

PROJECTS

Telegram Color Bot

GitHub Link

• Bot sends a 500x500 image with random xkcd or just random color or a color by HTML color code or name on xkcd, and can send the color of the day.

Converter of Distance Units

GitHub Link

• Made in Swift converter of distance units from the Metric system to the Imperial system and vice versa.

PROGRAMMING

C, C++ **Python**

Swift

lava



SKILLS

PostgreSQL

pandas matplotlib seaborn

Concurrency

OOP

Git

Linux

LANGUAGES

Russian (native) English (B2)

ABOUT ME

I have always wanted to be a programmer this is my dream: even when I do not want to do anything, it is always a pleasure to write a couple of hundred lines of code.

My path to MIPT was not so easy: I managed to enter the DAFE, and only after a year to transfer to DIHT. Studing at the new place was not only much harder, but also much more interesting, and this is the only thing which spurred my desire to study.

On the DIHT there are lots of interesting and useful computer science courses, so I have experience in different fields. The most interesting courses were "Computer Architecture and OS" and "Concurrency".

You can view my projects and progress on courses on my GitHub page.